# PRAGYA DAS

pragya.das@mines-ales.org, pragyadas0592@yahoo.com

# **OBJECTIVE**

To be associated with a progressive organization that gives me scope to enrich my skills and knowledge in the field of disaster management and related risk elements at a global level, to learn team dynamics and to work towards the growth of the organization.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master's of Science - Disaster Mangement and Environmental Impact (DAMGE) IMT MINES, Ales, France- M1 Completed With Highest Distinction 17.04/20.00 ECTS	2021 - 2023
Master's of Technology - Remote Sensing Banasthali University, Rajasthan India, Gold Medalist 80.47%	2015 - 2017
Bachelor's of Engineering - Civil Engineering RCET, Swami Vivekanand Technical University, Durg (C.G.) India, Honor's 78.78%	2010 - 2014

# **EXPERIENCE**

MS Summer Internship: IMT MINES, Research Center, Ales, France	June-July 2022
Part -Time Teacher: SVCAET, IGKV, Raipur, (C.G.), India	March- August 2021
Image Analyst: Centre for GIS Technology, Raipur, (C.G.), India	Aug 2017-Feb 2021
Master's Thesis with NRSC, ISRO, Hyderabad, Telangana, India	2016-2017
Lecturer at RECT, Raipur Swami Vivekanand Technical University, Durg, (C.G.) Inc	dia 2014-2015
Vocational Training: PWD, Raipur, Govt of Chhattisgarh, India	May-June 2013
Summer Internship: Water Resource Division, Rajnandgaon, Govt. of C.G., India	June 2012

# **PROFILE**

Upbeat Remote Sensing Researcher consistently striving to produce compliant deliverables in line with sketches, marked copies and written and verbal instructions. Adept at compiling, evaluating, modifying and analyzing data to support preparation of maps, tables, graphs, reports and databases. Articulate and organized professional with strong presentation skills and ability to comprehend, analyze and interpret documents with ease.

An unwavering commitment to the organization with the ability to build trusted relationships, resolve complex issues in the field of mapping disastrous events and analyzing them.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: R, Python, C++, C, MATLAB

Tools/Framework: ERDAS Imagine, Arc-GIS, QGIS, DGPS, Google sketch-up

General: Latex CED: Auto CAD

# AREA OF INTEREST

# **AREA OF INTEREST**

Risk Analysis/Management related to disastrous event, Disaster Mitigation and logistics supply management, Environment Conservation and Natural Resource Management using Image and Data Processing, Image Analysis, Map Production, Change Detection with and without models.

MS Summer Internship: June-July 2021 Hotspot Modeling of Malaria in Nigeria.

A bibliographical survey report on various models that were used in order to study the spread of malaria in Nigeria. Various environmental factors were taken into consideration while selecting the models based on which their efficiency was compared and studied for the internship report

Advisor: Mr. Nanlok Nimlang (PhD Research Fellow, IMT MINES, Research Center, Ales, France)

Master's Thesis: July 2016-July 2017

Hydrological Modeling of Trends in Seasonal Water Balance Components at River Basin Scale Using Time Series Land Use/Land Cover Data.

To Prepare datasets for the VIC model using MODIS data and to compute and compare the variation in water balancing components at river basin scale for predicting the LULC change and to generate the required accuracy of the model. (Mahanadi Basin of India)

Advisor: Dr. P.V. Raju, Scientist 'F', HOD Water Resource Division, National Remote Sensing Center, Hyderabad, India

Bachelor Thesis: July 2013 - April 2014

Comparative Study of Normal Concrete and Concrete prepared by addition of Agriculture Byproduct.

This project focuses on recycling agriculture residue by combining it with concrete and comparing its strength with normal concrete.

Advisor: Dr. Ashay D Shende, Assistant Professor, KDK College, Nagpur, MH, India

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

IMT MINES, Ales, France- M1 Completed With Highest Distinction 17.04/20.00 ECTS

**Gold Medalist in MTech (Remote Sensing)**, Banasthali Vidyapith, India 2018 **Academic Excellence Medal** in Bachelor of Engineering, RCET, India 2014

Certificate of Merit in Bachelor of Engineering, RCET, India 2013

# **PUBLICATIONS**

Projection of future precipitation over Gangotri glacier at Himalayan belt using CMIP5 Climate Model: 2021

Chapter 23" Advances in Hydrology and Climate Change: Historical Trends and New Approachesin Water Resources Management". Published by Taylor Francis Group. Authors: S.K. Chandniha.

M. Arora, L. Pal, A. Kumar, P. Das, G.K. Das

Climatic variability and its behavior are a complex phenomenon that is directly associated with uncertainties. In the climate change study, particularly in hydrological aspects, it is necessary to identify the parameters (predictors) that are directly or indirectly associated with predictands. The forecasted results are directly associated with the selection of predictors.

Hydrological Modelling of Mahanadi Basin and their tributary exist in Chhattisgarh and part of Odisha: 2018

Authors: Pragya Das, P.V. Raju and Chilka Sharma

9th National Seminar (Date and Year missing) IGKVV Raipur, Chhattisgarh India.

Change in crop sown in a region based on the water balance component trend analysis for a particular region, LULC can be managed efficiently.

**Green Building- Need of Present Era: 2013** 

Authors: Pragya Das and Bhupali Deshpande.

24th QUARK-2013, Nagpur, India

This presentation was based on eco-friendly building material that were proposed to be constructed eco friendly building and address the issue of environmental pollution Due to burning of Agricultural waste, self energy

sufficient by harnessing solar and wind energy and constructionmaterials used that can be recycled.

# **TRAININGS**

#### **INTERNATIONAL TRAININGS**

Mapping and Monitoring Lakes and Reservoirs with Satellite Observations, NASA's, USA, Applied RemoteSensing Training Program, Jan-Feb, 2022

Monitoring Coastal and Estuarine Water Quality Using Remote Sensing and In Situ, NASA's, USA, AppliedRemote Sensing Training Program, Nov-Dec 2021

Agricultural Crop Classification with Synthetic Aperture Radar and Optical Remote Sensing Data, NASA's, LEA Applied Remote Sensing Training Program, October 2021

Satellite Observations for Analyzing Natural Hazards on Small Island Nations, NASA's, USA, Applied RemoteSensing Training Program, August 2021

Hyperspectral Data for Land and Coastal Systems, **NASA's, USA, Applied Remote Sensing Training Program**, Jan-Feb, 2021

Remote Sensing of Coastal Ecosystems, NASA's, USA, Applied Remote Sensing Training Program, Aug-Sept, 2020

# **NATIONAL TRAININGS**

Digital Cartography Evolution of Location Intelligence, **Geo-spatial Awareness Hub**, India July 2020.

Remote Sensing and Imagery Solutions for Academia, CISCO and ARC-INDIA, June 2020.

Advances in Forestry, Agroforestry and Remote Sensing, IGKV, (C.G.) India May-June 2020.

Remote Sensing in crop Monitoring and assessment, IIRS, Dehradun, India May-June 2020.

Geospatial Technologies for Urban Planning, IIRS, Dehradun, India Feb-March 2016.

AUTOCAD, Raipur (C.G.), India May-June 2012

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth JUNE 05, 1993

Nationality Indian
Marital status Unmarried.

Languages known (Proficient) English, Hindi and (Beginner)French, German.

**Activities** Reading, Yoga, Calligraphy, Poetry and Exploring places.

# **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge. I will make it my earnest endeavor to discharge competently and carefully the duties you may be pleased to entrust me.

Place : Ales, FRANCE Pragya DAS

Date: